Mighty Little Defenders 11 – New Wild Cosmos.
The Last Flower Spark
Episode 45
Are you alright?
Your Majesty has returned.
The Xilan Tree…
How did it end up like this?
It’s all your fault for just playing in the mud
and failing to protect the Xilan Tree.
You were the ones who thought we were lazy—we aren’t lazy at all!
What? What?
Stop arguing; the top priority is to prevent the Xilan Tree from collapsing.
Even the Power of Light Cotton is useless this time.
We can’t let the Xilan Tree fall.
Why can’t so many of us stop the Xilan Tree from collapsing?
What should I do?
What can I do right now?
Can someone tell me what I should do?
That’s it!
So, when we Flower Babies evolve,
we have to answer the Xilan Tree’s questions.
How should I answer when the time comes?
Since the Xilan Tree can ask questions,
Maybe it can answer my question, too.
Can you help me?
Little one, you’d better go hide over there.
It’s dangerous here.
I…
Oh no.
Looks like I’m on my own.
Grow, Bamboo Node!
That’s Lan Baobao’s voice.
It really is him.
Weslie!
Thank goodness Weslie was in time.
Lan Baobao, what happened?
What are you doing here?
I’m going to the Trial Grounds
to ask the Xilan Tree how to save it.
Right.
When a Flower Baby is evolving,
it can communicate with the Xilan Tree.
That’s a good idea.
I’ll take you there.
Wolffy,
Lan Baobao and I will go up to the Trial Grounds to find another way.
You guys go down to a safe place and wait for me to come back.
Okay, we’ll wait for you.
Alright.
Lan Baobao, we need to hurry.
The door has opened; let’s go in quickly.
Flower Baby
Flower Baby, congratulations.
You have found a special Spark.
Now, you can choose to join the Flower Tribe or the Silt Tribe.
Xilan Tree, the withered leaves you shed are scattered everywhere outside.
Flowers keep withering, and a large hole has appeared in your roots.
Please tell me how to save you.
Xilan Tree, I beg you…
please answer me.
No one has ever asked me a question before.
How to save the Xilan Tree?
It doesn’t depend on me; it depends on you all.
This is the core of the Xilan Tree—the source of my life.
All this time,
the Spark formed by the fusion of the two tribes has sustained the Xilan Tree’s energy.
Could this seed be…the Flower Tribe and the Silt Tribe…
But because of their long-standing estrangement,
the Spark—which was meant to thrive through their connection—
gradually lost its bond.
My power has been fading away, too.
The destruction of the Xilan Tree…
is because of us.
Xilan Tree, just you wait—I will definitely save you.
What’s wrong?
Xilan Tree
Lan Baobao, are you okay?
I’m fine.
The connection to the Xilan Tree was temporarily interrupted by the earthquake.
But we should be able to continue.
Oh, right—I know how to save the Xilan Tree now.
I have to tell everyone right away.
Everyone, run!
Our home is gone.
The energy will gradually vanish from the top down.
In the end, even the land itself will disappear.
Xilan Tree
Why is it that no matter how hard we try,
we still can’t save the Xilan Tree?
Don’t give up.
Everyone,
I just heard the Xilan Tree’s voice.
It said that the destruction was caused by the estrangement
between the Flower Tribe and the Silt Tribe, leading to an imbalance in our Sparks.
So, everyone,
our two tribes must join hands and work together.
Let’s combine the power of both our tribes and infuse it into the Xilan Tree.
Give it a try!
I’ll give it a try.
The fused energy from the two tribes was actually absorbed by the Xilan Tree.
And it looks like the Xilan Tree has regained its vitality.
Let’s work together.
We’ll join in too.
Great! We did it.
No, there’s still not enough energy to reach the top.
It’s okay, I’m here.
My silt friend, where…
…are you?
There are so few people left in the Silt Tribe.
I’m sorry.
We shouldn’t have treated the Silt Tribe that way before.
I can evolve into the Silt Tribe form now.
Us too.
We possess the Silt Tribe Spark.
Why do you all have the Silt Tribe Spark?
Actually, besides the Flower Spark,
we also have the Silt Spark.
But we were afraid the mentors wouldn’t like it.
Baby, come here; there are beautiful flowers.
So we never mentioned it.
Now, please evolve according to your hearts’ desires.
But how are we Flower Babies supposed to climb up there?
And you need to be quick about it.
The Flower Baby Zone is running out of energy too.
Let me help you guys.
I’ll join in too.
If the Flower Baby Zone runs out of energy,
the Flower Babies won’t be able to evolve.
You two really need to hurry.
Oh no, I’m not going to make it in time.
Weslie, you can copy things, right?
Copy my evolved wings now.
Flower Baby Zone…
Go, go, go!
What?
Flower Babies
Lan Baobao
Give Lan Baobao back to me
What?
I’m going to call myself Lan Zhuzhu now
We’ll help too
Let’s work together
The silt nourishes the flowers
The flowers repay the silt with fragrance
The two tribes depend on each other
That is the meaning of the silt and the flowers’ existence
This is the Spark that belongs to all of us. Thank you
From now on, we must protect the Xilan Tree together
To be continued